Resume of Victor Kachan (Web developer, Java developer)

Personal details

Contact information

Name Victor Kachan E-mail setec.by@gmail.com

Date of birth 28 Aug 1982 **Skype** viktar.kachan

Nationality Belarus **Phone** +375—33—6645731

Languages Russian, English

Web version of resume http://stq.github.io

Education

2004-2005 Java Training Course at BSUIR/EPAM Joint Lab

2000-2005 Bachelor in Informatics (Mathematician, System programmer) at BSUIR(Minsk, Belarus)

Career summary

- Got over 10 years of practical experience with commercial web applications.
- Focused on web development technologies.
- Have major experience with back-end server frameworks and technologies (Java EE and others).

Main technology skills

Web/Markup: HTML, CSS

Web/Markup/Graphics: SVG, VML, HTML5 Canvas, WebGL, etc.

Web/Scripting: Javascript, Angular, Backbone, etc.

Java/Core: Java SE7 (Language, Concepts, API)

Java EE/Web: Servlet API, Spring MVC, Struts, Portlet API
Java EE/Web/Markup: JSP/EL/JSTL, Freemarker, Stripes, Wicket, Tiles

Java EE/Spring: Core (DI,AOP), Web(MVC, REST)

Database: RDBMS(SQL, PL/SQL)

Technology experience overview (interactive version)



Career (interactive version)

At Current Work

from Feb, 2015 to Jun, 2015, totally 4 month

Mar –2014– Mobile web site

Jan-2015 A web site targeting mobile and tablet platforms, presenting certain functionality of the well known social

4 month *network*.

Position: Tech lead

Participation: Technology revamp, features implementation.

Skills: Javascript (Angular, Lodash), Node.js (Express, Walk), HTML/CSS

At R-Style Lab

from Jan, 2014 to Feb, 2015, totally 1 year 1 month

Mar -2014- **eGov.kz v2**

Jan-2015 A web portal and kiosk-mode web app designed to provide a variety of governmental services to individual and

9 month organizations.

Position: Frontend Architect Achievement:

Participation: Development and support of toolchain, frameworks, web Suggested development

components. Team/PM assistance. methodologies which gave major

boost on development performance.

Skills: Javascript (Angular, Lodash), Node.js (Express, Walk), HTML/CSS

Team size: 38

Jan-2014 - <u>eGov.kz v2 prototype</u>

Apr-2014 Development of UI architecture and functionality.

4 month Position: Lead web developer Achievement:

Participation: Development of UI architecture and functionality. Separated frontend from java devs

so they could't ruin development

performance.

Skills: Javascript (Angular, Lodash), Node.js (Express, Walk), HTML/CSS

Team size: 3

At **Fitbit** from December, 2012 to December, 2013, totally 1 year and 1 month

Dec-2012 - Fitbit Corporate Wellness

Dec-2013 Web application for monitoring corporate personnel physical activity.

1 year and Position: Web developer, Java developer Achievement:

1 month Participation: Development, support, improvement of charts Major boost on web skills. Getting functionality. Development and support of various web

functionality. Development and support of various web over highcharts limits. Advanced widgets. Development of OAuth authentication flow. Agile methodology experience.

REST), Stripes, Guava, Java EE(Servlets, JMS), ORM (Hibernate), NoSQL (Cassandra)

Team size: 10-15

At Logic Way from May, 2010 to November, 2012, totally 2 years and 7 months

Nov-2012 Web client to manage customs database entities, made on base of existing Delphi application.

4 months Position: Lead developer Achievement:

Participation: Architecture development and support, base

Automatic DFM form to HTML layout

components development, team coordination. conversion.

Skills: Java, Wicket, HTML/CSS, Spring (DI, ORM), SQL, ORM (Hibernate), Javascript(jQuery), Java EE(Servlets)

Team size: 3-10

Jul-2012 - <u>Car insurance agency web services</u>

Jul-2012 Set of web services under Russian Car Insurance Association to be used by local agencies.

1 month Position: Java developer

Participation: Development of MQ manager and web services.

Skills: Java, Spring (DI), PL/SQL

Team size: 10-15

Jun-2012 - <u>CeConvergence</u>

Jun-2012 Web application for tracking and notification of accountant training courses.

1 month Position: Java developer

Participation: Development of various features.

Skills: Java, Spring (MVC, DI), PL/SQL

Team size: 5

May-2012 - YouTube downloader

May-2012 Software which allows downloading youtube videos.

1 month Position: Java developer

Participation: Research, development. Skills: Java, YouTube API, FLV, Video encoding

Team size: 1

Feb-2012 - Mind.com webinars

Apr-2012 Online webinars system.

3 months Position: Java developer, Web developer

Participation: Development of various features and improvements.

Skills: Java, HTML/CSS, SVG, VML, RaphaelGWT, Raphael, Guava, Hibernate, Apache Batic, Java EE(Servlets)

Team size: 8

Sep-2011 - Whiteboard module for Mind.com webinars

Jan-2012 Whiteboard module for sharing drawings, images and documents at web video conference system.

5 months Position: Lead developer, Team management Achievement:

Participation: Technology assistance, project management, Project management skills, SVG

development. experience.

Skills: Java, HTML/CSS, SVG, VML, RaphaelGWT, Raphael, Guava, ORM(Hibernate), Apache Batic, Javascript(jQuery), JavaEE(Servlets)

Team size: 3

Aug-2011 - Automated fine payment system

Aug-2011 Module for fine payment in customs control application.

1 month Position: SQL developer

Participation: Development of PL/SQL services.

Skills: PL/SQL Team size: 1

Jun-2011 -**PeopleNet logistics tracking**

Jul-2011

Web application which provide different services for logistics — tracking, optimization.

2 months

Position: Contractor, Java developer

Achievement:

Participation: Web service development. Contractor experience, GWT experience. Skills: Java, SQL, OSCi, ORM (Hibernate), Spring (DI, ORM), GWT, Ext GWT, Portlets, Java EE(Servlets, EJB)

Team size: 20-30

Dec-2010 -

Severstal ESK Contractor Management System

May-2011

Web client application for contractors browsing and management (variety of specific business domain actions).

6 months

Position: Java developer, Team lead

Achievement:

Participation: Portal server maintenance, portlet implementation

Helped customer to fix server failure

assistance, team training. after midnight. Skills: Java, XML/XSD, WSDL, Axis, IBM XML Beans, JSP/EL/JSTL, HTML/CSS, Javascript(jQuery), Portlets, Java EE(Servlets)

Team size: 5-6

Jun-2010 -

MSC Council Archive

Nov-2010 6 months

Web application to store, secure, manage, browse and share official documentation.

Position: SQL developer, Java developer, Web developer, Team lead

Achievement:

Participation: Development of UI BREAD engine and UI implementation. Frontend

application DB/BL/Services development. Development of IBM ICM interface utility (ICM operations interface, data

Made AOP-based data caching for better performance.

export/import/synchronization).

Skills: Java, XML/XSD, Freemarker, HTML/CSS, Javascript, SQL, IBM CM, Javassist, Java EE(Servlets)

Team size: 3

May-2010 -

MSC Internal Affairs Archive

May-2010

DB archive application to secure and manage official documentation.

1 month

Position: DB developer, Java developer

Achievement:

Participation: DB structure implementation and support. Development of database Good DB experience. export/import utility.

Skills: Java, SQL, PL/SQL

Team size: 2

At Specific Group AG

from March, 2009 to April, 2010, totally 1 year and 2 months

Mar-2009 -

European Gate

Apr-2010

Server application for format conversion of financial transaction. With web client for control/monitoring.

1 year and

Position: Technical writer, Java developer, Web developer

Achievement:

2 months

Participation: Project documentation, status feedback, code review, architecture

review. Consulting branch department. Introduction of CI process.

Web client improvements, wicket model optimization. Conversion

compatibility testing framework development.

Documentation process introduction. Multiple code

and process optimizations.

Skills: ANTLR, UML, Java, Spring (DI, ORM), Wicket, HTML/CSS, ORM (Hibernate), Java EE(Servlets)

Team size: 5-7

At **Agava**

from August, 2008 to November, 2008, totally 4 months

Sep-2008 - Rebot.ru web development

Nov-2008 News feed reader, which knows what news will be interesting to the user.

3 months Position: Web developer Achievement:

Participation: WSDL development, web frontend development, integration with

Agava CRM.

Boost on HTML/CSS skills.

Skills: Java, Javascript(jQuery), HTML/CSS, Java EE (Servlets, Web services), Axis, Axis WSF

Team size: 2-3

Aug-2008 - Adbroker.ru instant search

Aug-2008 Web advertisements management system: ads trade, management, control, statistics.

1 month Position: Web developer, Java developer Achievement:

Participation: Development of instant search.

Introduced minor performance optimization on instant search.

Skills: Java, Java EE (Servlets, EJB, Web services), ORM (Hibernate), SQL, JBoss Seam, Axis, Javascript(jQuery), HTML/CSS, XSLT

Team size: 1

At **Generation-P consulting ltd.** from February, 2008 to June, 2008, totally 5 months

Feb-2008 - Web application for job surveys service

Jun-2008 Online survey for a big job agency. Featuring automatic survey management, analysis and report tools.

5 months Position: Consultant, Java developer Achievement:

Participation: Architecture optimization: transaction safety, deadlocks, memory Successfully improved usage, performance, clustering. Performance and functional performance and stability testing tools. Code review. EJB 2.0 upgrade to EJB 3.0. Spring of application.

integration.

Skills: Java, Java EE (Servlets, JMS, EJB), ORM (Hibernate), SQL, Clustering (JOnAS), Spring (DI), JUnit

Team size: 4

At EPAM, Hyperion Department

from September, 2007 to January, 2008, totally 5 months

Sep-2007 - <u>Hyperion Strategic Finance / Profitability module</u>

Jan-2008 Web client software for development of financial plan.

5 months Position: Java developer, Web developer Achievement:

Participation: Module component development: UI, business logic, testing

Got some Java EE experience.

and integration.

Skills: Java, Java EE (Servlets, JMS, EJB, JSF), ORM (TopLink), SQL, Bindows

Team size: 15-20

At **EPAM, Travel Solutions Department** April, 2005 to August, 2007 - 2 years and 5 months

Oct-2006 - Travel Distribution Platform

Aug-2007 Platform for online booking web applications.

11 months Position: Java developer Achievement:

Participation: Design and development of booking services. Assisting with Good experience with web

integration. services.

Skills: UML, Java, Struts 1.x, JSP/EL/JSTL, JUnit, WSDL, Apache Axis)

Team size: 10-15

Jan–2006 – <u>Vail Resorts call center</u>

Sep-2006 Web frontend with BREAD-functionality for reservation management service.

9 months Position: Web developer, Java developer Achievement:

Participation: Research and architecture on web communication layer. Introduction of custom model-

Development and support of custom BREAD MVC framework. view javascript framework.

Skills: Javascript, Java, JSP/EL/JSTL, HTML/CSS, Struts 1.x, JUnit, WSDL, Apache Axis, Java EE (Servlets)

Team size: 5-10

Jul-2005 - Scandinavian Airlines booking

Dec-2005 Web application for flight itinerary search and reservation. Have original design.

6 months Position: Web developer, Java developer Achievement:

Participation: Presentation layer and business logic implementation. Perfect teamwork, happy customer.

Skills: Javascript, DWR, Java, JSP/EL/JSTL, HTML/CSS, Struts 1.x, JUnit, WSDL, Apache Axis, Java EE (Servlets)

Team size: 5-10

Apr-2005 - South African Airways booking

Jun-2005 Web application for flight itinerary search and reservation.

3 months Position: Java developer Achievement:

Participation: Presentation layer and business logic implementation. Promoted JSP Tag unit tests.

Skills: Java, JSP/EL/JSTL, HTML/CSS, Struts 1.x, JUnit, WSDL, Apache Axis, Java EE (Servlets)

Team size: 5-10

Web version of my work profile:

Please visit my web site http://stq.github.io to see web version of this resume, which is more comfortable to read. To see source code, use this link: http://stq.github.io/index-full.html

With best regards, Victor Kachan (setec.by@gmail.com)

Last updated Dec, 2014